I'd just like to share some
insights that I've been having. It
seems like every day, for almost
two years now, I've thought deeply
about every day.
And every day, I somehow always end
up in the same place, feeling so
responsible for
all the horrible things that have
happened to my wife and all the
ways in which she feels
not heard and disrespected. The
enormity of it all has never been
missed upon me.
The thing that I don't feel anybody
knows is that I understand this.
One insight I had just today was
the idea or awareness that I know
earlier in my previous
years when I got into deep spaces
of depression, and I would withdraw
and not communicate,
essentially from a place of "I
didn't want to bother anybody," but
it comes out of my
pores, you know, I don't know, my
energy comes out of my pores,
anyway, point being, I found
myself, in those moments, resorting
to behaviors and patterns that I
learned as a kid, I was
behaving like a little kid, I was
shutting up, I was to be seen and
not heard, I was
trying to hide and not be noticed,
but at the same time, I just wanted
to talk about
feeling forgotten, feeling not
worth anything, because if you keep
forgetting about me, who
am I? I just didn't know how to
express myself, and I regret that
deeply.
I had the inability to, one, calm
myself down to a level where I
could even speak English.
The hysterics get me a lot of
times, and I get full of mucus and
snot, and the hysteria
sets in and everything goes down my
toilet after that. My point being
is that, from that awareness about
the behavior as a child and the
behaviors
and things I do, perfect example is
somebody starts speaking, and I
just jump right in
over the top of them, and that is a
defense mechanism, when I feel
threatened, that's
what that is, and in the past when
I did that, that was subconscious
behavior, that was something
I was completely just not even
aware of, I didn't even know I was
doing it.
Number one, I didn't know I was
interrupting, number two, I didn't
know the level of energy
I was bringing and how that would
be perceived, and so on and so
forth.
The other thing that is impossible
to communicate, honestly, unless
you were to hang out with
me and spend time with me, is that
I don't have that nervous vibe
anymore, I'm not freaking
out about things like I used to, I
mean, dealing with my life right
now is extremely heavy,
and the events and what's going on
trigger a lot of my depression,
it's here, it's hanging
out with me, I won't lie about
that, in fact I'm just not going to
hide anything anymore,
I'll ask questions, I'll tell you
the truth, always, I'll always tell
the truth.
I was in a dark place and had a
global pandemic and I'm not making
any excuses for anything
but where I found myself with self-
medication at that time, I reflect
back now and don't
know what the hell I was thinking,
part of it was the depression lying
to me telling
me that I'm not worth it, that I'm
not worth going to the doctor and
getting professional
care, that I should just wallow in
my pain and suffering, and the
self-medication was
just, you know, to numb you out so
you didn't feel, I mean you just
didn't feel like Charlie
Brown 24/7, just like melancholy,
you know, anyhow, I'm getting eaten
alive by mosquitoes
and I'm allergic to them so I'm
going to cut this off now, I'm a
different person,
the thing is nobody will listen,
everybody looks at me with the same
eyes and it's really
sad. I get emotional only because I
know how hard I've worked to get
where I am right now and
believe it or not I'm really happy
with myself and honestly proud of
myself.
I regained my composure in a moment
that was not something I used to be
able to do, that
was pretty triggering, anyway, I
just want to wrap up and say that I
wish, I wish I could
be with my family, I wish I could
be close so they could, so they
could meet me again,
honestly, that's all I want, I just
want to meet again, okay, I think
that's it, I can
see twinkling light on the other
side of the valley, just below the
ridge line, I just
saw one, so that means it's time to
say goodnight, okay, peace out, boy
scout.